ALLSTON SCHWARTZ

Charleston, South Carolina 29407 | (843) 224-8492

PROFILE

Though I've worked in multiple disciplines, my focus lies in front-end development and interaction design. I have a passion for solving problems, constantly perfecting my craft, and producing work that I can be proud of. I'm currently seeing to expand my skills in a software development role, so if you're interested in hiring me, check out my work, and let's get in touch.

EDUCATION

The Iron Yard. / Frontend Developer

January 2015 - March 2015

Charleston, SC

Georgia State University

August 1995 - May 1998

BA in English Literature and a minor in Theatre Arts (GPA 3.75) Atlanta, Ga

SKILLS

PROGRAMMING:

HTML 5 CSS3/SASS JavaScript jQuery Angular Backbone Underscore

TOOLS:

Git/Github

12 week, intensive Frontend Development program

Command Line

Version Control Bower/NPM

AJAX

DESIGN:

Bootstrap

CMS:

WordPress

CONT. ED.

Treehouse: PHP; WordPress; HTML; CSS

CodeAcademy: HTML; CSS; JavaScript

Freelance Developer

Frontend Developer

Charleston, SC Mar 2015-Present

EXPERIENCE

- Taught myself WordPress and PHP
- Designed and created customized WordPress website for attorney
- Updating local Cub Scout website

Charleston Real Estate and Law, LLC

Property Manager

Charleston, SC Jun 2015-Feb 2016

Maintained leases and tenant needs

Addlestone Hebrew Academy

Teaching Assistant

Charleston, SC

Feb 2013 - Jan 2015

- Created recorded text for students with language based learning disorders.
- Conducted small group and individual classroom activities with students based on differentiated learning needs to ensure all students were learning at their full potential.
- Participated in ongoing staff training sessions.
- Organized parent-teacher conferences to maximize student learning opportunities and develop forwardthinking plans to correct ongoing issues.
- Employed assessment tools and proactive strategies to improve instruction methods.
- Assisted in producing curriculum that met state goals as well as the needs of the individual students.
- Worked with groups ranging from as little as 6 to as large as 30.

Inside the Envelope

CEO/Invitation Consultant

Charleston, SC Oct 2008 - Present

- Expertise in areas ranging from business administration to marketing invitations and creative services.
- Entrepreneur who through effective business planning, creative sales techniques, and innovative marketing, cultivated relationships with clients and vendors that gamered continued business and positive referrals.
- Recognized by clients and colleagues as a consummate professional with a high degree of personal integrity.
- Known for a contagious passion for excellence, ensuring consistent quality customer service to internal and external clients and attainment of individual and team goals.

RONT END DEVELOPER